Abamitchew Tomas Belay

Software Engineer

I'm a passionate software engineer driven to build optimized application that bring life to ideas and solve real-word problems. . My experiences have built my strength in clean coding, collaboration, and analytical thinking. I'm a keen learner and strongly believe in consistent practical experiences. Thus, I relish working in challenging environments where I can stretch my problem-solving skills and learn from others.

amitchew@gmail.com

+251919409128

TensorFlow

8

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer iWork Technologies

03/2021 - Present https://www.iworkplc.com

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Tasks

- Prepare summary statistics and graphical representations to perform preliminary investigations on data.
- Implement Machine Learning algorithms for customer segmentation from historical data as well as designed and implemented algorithms to forecast sales and demand
- Developing and implementing highly responsive user interface components using React Js for ERP (Enterprise Resource Planning) web app
- Responsible for developing a store replenishment Shopify app; by using ReactJs, Polaris and Shopify CLI

Junior Software Developer ZayTech

02/2019 - 07/2019 Internship Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

IIILEITIS

- Writing mobile application interface codes using Dart following the Flutter framework.
- Maintain and update project dependencies as well as fix any conflicts
- Design and develop new custom components to meet project requirements

LANGUAGES

Science (10/2021) *Udemy Certeficate*

CERTEFICATION

Stanford Online via Coursera

Machine Learning (10/2021)

SKILLS

Pandas

English Amharic
Full Professional Proficiency Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Phyton

Sci-kit Learn

Machine Learning A-Z™: Hands on Phyton & R in Data

INTERESTS

Astronomy Robotics Reading Hiking

EDUCATION

BSc, Computer EngineeringAddis Ababa Science and Technology University

08/2015 - 12/2020

Courses

- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Operating Systems
- Digital Logic Design
- Microprocessor and Assembly Language
- Embedded Systems
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Distributed Systems
- Circuit Analysis
- VLSI Systems and Design
- Computer Architecture